<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tampa Bay's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Karen &amp; Joe Donovan, a top Real Estate Agent in Tampa Bay, shares their own internal real estate agent training for free. Their Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 12:04:42 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 12:04:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Let Cigarette Odors Cause Your Home Sale to Go up in Smoke</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/P_2cr6j9cZ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you smoke cigarettes in your home, the odors this habit leaves behind could cause your home sale to go up in smoke. Thankfully, there are three cleaning tips that can help alleviate this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a cigarette smoker, you may have become smell-blind to the odors this habit can leave behind in your home. This can pose a big problem when it comes time to sell because non-smoking buyers are sure to notice this residual aroma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure cigarette odors don’t cause your home sale to go up in smoke, there are three key tips you should follow when you list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Have a full professional cleaning of your heating and cooling system.&lt;/strong&gt; Cigarette smoke will get trapped in your home’s HVAC unit itself, so simply changing out the air filter won’t be enough if you hope to rid your house of odors. Having a professional clean the ductwork, and the unit itself, will be your ticket to fresh-smelling air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Seal and repaint your walls and ceilings.&lt;/strong&gt; Your home’s walls and ceilings can trap unpleasant-smelling nicotine particles, and painting alone won’t be enough to undo this effect. Instead, seal your walls first with a primer (like Kilz) and then add your fresh coat of paint after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Launder or steam-clean cloth items, carpet, and furniture in your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Your drapes, chairs, couches, carpet, and more will all absorb the smell of cigarette smoke over time. Giving each of these items a thorough, professional cleaning will give a huge boost to your home’s overall freshness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Trapped odors from cigarette smoke can pose a big problem when it comes time to sell, because non-smoking buyers are sure to notice this residual aroma.%20localhost:4000/today-on-keeping-in-tune-with-market-3.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Trapped odors from cigarette smoke can pose a big problem when it comes time to sell, because non-smoking buyers are sure to notice this residual aroma.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus tip: Wipe down flat surfaces, knick-knacks, and light bulbs in your home. You may be surprised to learn that these items can contribute to how your home smells, but the difference that cleaning these things can make will speak for itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 14:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/today-on-keeping-in-tune-with-market-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/today-on-keeping-in-tune-with-market-3.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Were Thankful for All of You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2RbeQNFZUpI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time of year, we think about how much we have to be grateful for. Thanksgiving is a time to give, a time to love, and a time to reflect on things that mean the most in your life. This Thanksgiving, we are especially treasuring the weeks, hours, and minutes of time that we are able to spend with those that we care about. To all of our family, friends, neighbors, clients, and co-workers: We wish you a truly beautiful and bountiful Thanksgiving. We wrote a song called “You Are” that we think fits perfectly this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/were-thankful-for-all-of-you_16.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/were-thankful-for-all-of-you_16.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keeping In Tune With The Market: Inside the Mind of a FSBO Seller</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jSVAKHPB4Y4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you, as an agent, convince a For Sale By Owner seller to work with you? It starts by jumping inside the mind of a FSBO seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another episode of “Keeping In Tune With The Market.” Today, we’re going to get inside the mind of a homeowner who wants to list their home as For Sale By Owner (FSBO).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you like to get a listing this month? Sure, the market is tight and there’s not very much inventory, so what is the best way for you to get a new listing where you could help a homeowner sell their house?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many agents shy away from FSBO listings because they think that when they go to those homeowners, they’ll get their heads bitten off. That’s actually not the case. By getting inside the head of a FSBO seller, we can understand that they might be a little less scary than you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would a person consider selling their home on their own instead of turning it over to a Realtor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reason is to save on commission. A lot of them are just confident that they could sell on their own because, perhaps, they’ve sold cars or homes before. They might not know a good agent, or they might have had a bad experience with one. Many FSBO sellers feel as though they have a bottom line to reach and that they can’t afford to pay an agent. In that case, we have to show the owner how we can make them even more money than they could get on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They might also think that if they can’t sell it on their own, then they can just turn it over to an agent. They might give it a few weeks to a couple months to try to sell on their own. In this case, find out what their motivation is. How soon do they need to move? Where are they going? Get an idea of how long they want to try it on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many agents shy away from FSBO listings because they think that when they go to those homeowners, they’ll get their heads bitten off.%20localhost:4000/keeping-in-tune-with-market-inside-mind.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many agents shy away from FSBO listings because they think that when they go to those homeowners, they’ll get their heads bitten off.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, they feel like they want to get a particular bottom line. You will really be helpful to them if you can put them in touch with a mortgage broker or a financial expert so they can see how much money they really need from the sale of their house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FSBO sellers aren’t as scary as you think. If you try to get on the other side of the able, get into their heads, and think about what their thought processes are, it might be a little easier for you to approach them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more information about working with FSBO sellers, I have a couple of trainers who have great plans. Just reach out to me, and I’ll be glad to send you that information. If you’d like to set up a strategy meeting to plan out your business for this year, we can set that up over coffee. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 10:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/keeping-in-tune-with-market-inside-mind.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/keeping-in-tune-with-market-inside-mind.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get More Listings in 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q6n9UEVlYnU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get more business, there is a key mantra you need to apply. That mantra is, “See. Call. Send.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the best ways to get listings?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’ll be going over three tips you need to know to get more listings in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question you need to ask yourself is, “Who are the best people to get listings from?” A lot of people will say you should look into things like cold calling and door knocking. These things are fine, but the fact is that about 75% of your listings will come from people who already know you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that the majority of listings you get will come from friends, family, co-workers, and other people in your sphere of influence. The people who know you are the ones who will do business with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The people who know you are the ones who will do business with you.%20localhost:4000/how-to-get-more-listings-in-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The people who know you are the ones who will do business with you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s move on to the three ways to get listings from these people. It all comes down to the mantra: “See. Call. Send.” Let me expand a little on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. See.&lt;/strong&gt; Checking in with the people you know will help you stay connected. It doesn’t always have to be about real estate. The important thing is that you are keeping in touch and maintaining these relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Call.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to give the people you know a call every once in a while. The market has gone up dramatically, so consider asking people if they’re curious about their home’s value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Send.&lt;/strong&gt; Distribute newsletters and notifications to people in your sphere of influence via the mail. The mail you send can be informative, educational, and entertaining. While you’re at it, you could even start sending out videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 12:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-get-more-listings-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-get-more-listings-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check Out This New Music Video Featuring the Donovan 3</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oZGx0K4_gLk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the Donovan 3 are singing their rendition of “Do You Believe in Christmas?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re almost to the end of the year, and the holiday season is in full swing with happy people everywhere. Here at Donovan Home Sales, there’s something magic in the air.  If you hear a song and start to hum along, it may just be the Donovan 3 singing their rendition of “Do You Believe in Christmas?” If you want a reason to get into the holiday spirit and enjoy a catchy, festive tune, go ahead and watch our new music video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 12:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/check-out-this-new-music-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/check-out-this-new-music-video.html</guid>
        
        <category>The Donovan Team</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Break Into Real Estate Without Breaking the Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zcMX-xKYHjI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.” Today’s question is: How can a new real estate agent break into the business without breaking the bank?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s question is: How can a new real estate agent break into the business without breaking the bank?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve got your brand-new real estate license and you’re excited to begin. Then, things start popping up. You’re told you must subscribe to this coach or pay for that class. The issue is that all of these kinds of things cost money. But I’m here to tell you that all is not lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get great training for free. It is possible. The first thing I recommend is that you look into a program called RealtyJuggler. When you sign up at www.RealtyJuggler.com you can get a 90-day subscription for free, and it really does the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It is possible to get great training for free.%20localhost:4000/break-into-real-estate-without-breaking.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It is possible to get great training for free.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RealtyJuggler will help you learn how to consistently prospect, stay organized, develop a database, and have a great mindset. There are a lot of great features on the site. In the contact section, you can add all of your friends, relatives, neighbors, coworkers, and anyone else right into your database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve plugged in the email addresses of all of these contacts, you can begin to prospect. I’ve got a couple of resources I’d like to share that can help you do this. First, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mikeferrytv.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.MikeFerryTV.com&lt;/a&gt; is a great, free resource for scripts, dialogue, and training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another place to get information is on Kevin Ward’s video blog. And, of course, we can’t forget Mr. Tom Ferry. Visit his website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomferry.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for some great tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have our own career-building video blog, which you can find here. If you would like some training on a particular topic, you can feel free to ask me a question at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 11:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/break-into-real-estate-without-breaking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/break-into-real-estate-without-breaking.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Identify and Handle a Stroke</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5aahrDDYNyc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing what to do when you spot a stroke is critical—the right knowledge could save a life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do something a little different for today’s episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.” Today, I want to talk about a very serious subject: strokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re with family over the holiday season when suddenly you notice a loved one’s face beginning to droop on one side—one side of their body appears weak and they’re now slurring their speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do? First, it’s time to call 911. These warning signs should never be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago when my own mother began exhibiting these symptoms, my sisters were thankfully able to recognize the signs and get her immediate medical treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is critical that people who have had or are having a stroke receive medical attention within the first three hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I have first-hand experience where another family member was not so fortunate. My sister-in-law had a stroke around the same time as my mother. She was out of the town at the time and went to a walk-in clinic where they told her it was probably just her back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Warning signs should never be ignored.%20localhost:4000/how-to-identify-and-handle-stroke.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Warning signs should never be ignored.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They sent her home and she suffered a massive stroke. As a result of not receiving prompt and immediate attention, her injuries will be long-term, if not permanent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be wondering why I’ve chosen to talk about this when my usual subjects relate to real estate. The truth is that real estate is about family and home. That’s why today I chose to share this information with you—to protect your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to spot and handle a stroke is to remember “F.A.S.T.,” which stands for face drooping, arm weakness, speech difficulty, and time to call 911.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it is you or a family member experiencing these symptoms, do not wait. Getting immediate emergency medical treatment is absolutely key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you and your family stay happy, healthy, and able to enjoy your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-identify-and-handle-stroke.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-identify-and-handle-stroke.html</guid>
        
        <category>Stroke</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are Some Subtle Ways to Get Sellers to Do What You Want?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TrHAKfR4Z1U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a seller whose house needs work, there are five tactful ways to get them to do what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about five tricks you can use to get a seller to do what you want. Well, they’re not really “tricks” — they’re more like tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you have a seller and you know there are things on their house that need to be changed or fixed. Either you saw them when you first walked in the door, they were brought to your attention as time went by and you looked closer at the property, or a fellow Realtor brought it up to you during an inspection. In any case, should you lay it all on the seller with your bottom line very sternly and risk them getting annoyed with you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Help your seller feel that you’re understanding.%20localhost:4000/what-are-some-subtle-ways-to-get.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Help your seller feel that you’re understanding.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s probably not the best way of doing things. There are five ways to be more tactful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Be compassionate.&lt;/strong&gt; You might not know what the situation is with that particular seller. They may be getting divorced, going through a job transfer, dealing with a death in the family, etc. If you do know, you need to be compassionate, give them a little space, and help them feel that you’re understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Create a to-do list.&lt;/strong&gt; I had a seller recently whose house wasn’t too bad, but we got a lot of feedback about its patio and yard being unkempt. Instead of just telling them they had to do some repainting and lay some sod down, we sat down with them and made a to-do list. They were on board with it, and they did most of the things on that list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Involve the seller.&lt;/strong&gt; Ask them what they think they can do to help with the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Suggest some low-cost alternatives.&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe it’s just a paint job and some power washing. Maybe you know a handyman who can help them. Maybe they need a low-cost storage unit to help them declutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Offer options.&lt;/strong&gt; If there is a seller who is elderly and can’t make the necessary repairs, then you make an alternative solution such as a credit at the closing. This way they won’t have to do a lot of work if they feel as though they don’t have the energy or the monetary wherewithal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to seeing you at the next episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.” Until then, make it a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 13:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-are-some-subtle-ways-to-get.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-are-some-subtle-ways-to-get.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tampa Bay Realtor Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keeping in Tune With the Market: How to Get Your Offer Accepted Without Breaking the Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pj9ClE0eVbc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a homebuyer competing against other offers on the same home, here are three strategies you can use to make your offer stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m answering a question from Amanda Fabian, who asks, “How do I get my offer accepted when there are four other competing offers on a home?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, congratulations to Amanda, who will receive a $10 Panera gift card for her question being chosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get your offer accepted when there are other competing offers on the same home, I have three strategies you can use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make your offer as competitive as you can without going over your budget.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re going with a higher financing amount, you must be competitive against someone who might be putting more cash into the deal. Also, make sure you have your pre-approval letter and that you submit it at the same time you put your offer in. Your offer must be as strong as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Find out from the other agent or owner what their hot buttons are.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, does the owner want a quick closing or do they need extra time? When you structure your offer, make sure to add that in. Does the owner have a special appliance they want to take with them? Stress that the appliance can go with the owner and you don’t insist on having it stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Write a personal note from the heart.&lt;/strong&gt; This one is my secret weapon. When you do this, find out a little bit about the owner and share with them some information about your family and how you will love the home as much as they did. If you have a cute little kid or puppy, include pictures of them in the note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your offer must be as strong as possible.%20localhost:4000/keeping-in-tune-with-market-how-to-get.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your offer must be as strong as possible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a real estate question that’s on your mind, don’t hesitate to email it to me. If I answer it in a future video, you’ll receive a $10 gift card. Until next time, make it a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 14:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/keeping-in-tune-with-market-how-to-get.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/keeping-in-tune-with-market-how-to-get.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tampa Bay Realtor Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Season's Greetings from the Donovan Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BQnbCfiCxr4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may surprise some of you to know that we at the Donovan Team are as passionate about music as we are about real estate! Please check out this year’s Singing Christmas Card!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Ask us a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meeting/&quot;&gt;Set up a Skype or coffee meeting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the holidays in full swing, we wanted to share something special with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many of you may know from prior posts - when we aren’t busy helping our clients buy and sell real estate or helping our team members design their dream real estate career,  we love writing and performing music!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are proud to present our 5th Annual Singing Christmas card for your musical entertainment! This year’s presentation is entitled: “Memories Are Evergreen”. With guest vocalist Paul Donovan on lead, Joe Donovan, musical producer on harmonica, and Karen Donovan, singer/song writer, on backup vocals. Warning - this video could bring a tear to your eye as you recall happy memories from your past!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/mU4yjm5AOCc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to hear the track and see the music video, which is comprised of our home movies from years ago. You may even recognize a few members of the Donovan Brothers Realty team in it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Wishing you and your loved ones a Christmas &amp;amp; Holiday Season that is truly Evergreen!%20localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-donovan-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Wishing you and your loved ones a Christmas &amp;amp; Holiday Season that is truly Evergreen!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all of us at the Donovan Team, we’d like to wish  all of our Clients, Friends, Colleagues &amp;amp; Loved ones a Blessed Holiday and Happy and Healthy New Year and may all your wishes come true!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if we can help you or a Real Estate Colleague you care about with Real Estate endevors 2017 - don’t hesitate to give us a call!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 14:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-donovan-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-donovan-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>The Donovan Team</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
