<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Tampa Bay Real Estate Podcast with Karen & Joe Donovan</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Donovan Home Sales, Inc. - your professional Tampa Bay Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Karen & Joe Donovan</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-07-02 09:38:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Karen & Joe Donovan</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Karen@homesbydonovan.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Tampa Bay Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Donovan Home Sales, Inc. - your professional Tampa Bay Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Time-Management Technique to Enhance Your Life & Business</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-time-management-technique-to-enhance-your-life-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-17 15:31:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re all given the same 24 hours each day, but where you direct your time is something to think about. In response to some questions I’ve received, today I’m going to discuss time management and organization a little further. 

So where do you start? First things first—you’ll want to get out a pencil and paper and make a list of where your time is currently going. Make note of your work hours, family commitments, and other activities. 

Once this is accomplished, assess the areas where your time is going to waste. This part of the exercise will allow you to pin down the essentials, determine where your time is needlessly going, and find out where you want it to go.    

“When you’re able to highlight the activities that enrich your life, jot down when you’re going to devote time to those things or when you’ll be naturally engaged in them.”

When you’re able to highlight the activities that enrich your life, jot down when you’re going to devote time to those things or when you’ll be naturally engaged in them. 

Take the total number of hours you spend immersed in those activities and add them to the number of hours you sleep each day. Then, subtract your grand total from 24, which will tell you how many hours you have left over to practice real estate sales. 

Whether you have four, six, or 12 hours remaining each week, let me know. This is where you can begin to make optimal use of those hours and find greater success in your real estate business. 

So again, find out what that number is, and give me a call at 516-822-1442 so you can take the next step. For any other questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I look forward to speaking with you! 

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Managing your time in a more effective manner is as simple as making a list and doing a little math. What do I mean by that? Find out in today’s video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Managing your time in a more effective manner is as simple as making a list and doing a little math. What do I mean by that? Find out in today’s video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips That Will Have People Calling You Back in No Time</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-tips-that-will-have-people-calling-you-back-in-no-time.html</link>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-11 11:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Long+Island)/Videos/2019/Long+Island+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+People+To+Call+You.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you keep calling someone but they won’t call you back, what can you do to get ahold of them? Here are three tips that will solve this problem.  

First, you can call, hang up if you get their voicemail, call again, hang up again if you get their voicemail, and then call one more time. What’s the point of calling three times in a row? Speaking for myself, if my husband calls me three times in a row, there’s probably an urgent reason why and it means I should pick up the phone. 

“Sooner or later, they’re bound to call you back.”

Another option is to use Slydial. With this program, you can connect directly to their voicemail and leave a message without calling them. 

If either of these tips fail, you can always just knock on their door. If they’re not home, try leaving a note. Sooner or later, they’re bound to call you back.

If you’d like to talk more about this topic or you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to call or email me. In the meantime, make it a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Long+Island)/Videos/2019/Long+Island+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+People+To+Call+You.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Long+Island)/Videos/2019/Long+Island+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+People+To+Call+You.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you keep calling someone but they won’t call you back, don’t worry—here are a few tips you can use to get ahold of them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you keep calling someone but they won’t call you back, don’t worry—here are a few tips you can use to get ahold of them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Avoid a Low Appraisal</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-avoid-a-low-appraisal.html</link>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-25 09:38:43 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
Whether you’re a buyer, a seller, or an agent, the last thing you want is to receive a low appraisal on a home you recently sold or wanted to buy.

I just had a buyer’s agent tell me that they simply “let the appraiser handle that.” That’s absolutely the wrong thing to do—in fact, there are three crucial things you must do to avoid a low appraisal in the first place:


  Make sure the appraiser has a detailed list of all the features, amenities, and improvements of the home. Sellers, provide your Realtor with that list so they can give it to the appraiser.
  Find out if the appraiser would like comparable sales. Even if they say no, provide them anyway. Do this before they go out to appraise the property, and make sure to use sensible comps—not ones that are too high, low, or far away. You want the appraiser to be able to utilize them in case they’re not familiar with your area.
  Provide the appraiser with any supporting documentation. A client’s home had an additional lot, and if we hadn’t provided the survey for it, the appraisal would not have been accurate.


“The last thing you want is to receive a low appraisal on a home.”​​​​​​If all else fails and you still receive a low appraisal, there are still other things you can do. We’ll be detailing these in a future video, so stay tuned!

In the meantime, feel free to reach out to us if you have any questions or would like further information. We look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You won’t have to be worried about receiving a low appraisal if you follow these three tips.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You won’t have to be worried about receiving a low appraisal if you follow these three tips.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don't Let Cigarette Odors Cause Your Home Sale to Go up in Smoke</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/today-on-keeping-in-tune-with-market-3.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-04 14:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Don%2527t+Let+Your+Listing+Go+Up+In+Smoke.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you smoke cigarettes in your home, the odors this habit leaves behind could cause your home sale to go up in smoke. Thankfully, there are three cleaning tips that can help alleviate this issue.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


If you’re a cigarette smoker, you may have become smell-blind to the odors this habit can leave behind in your home. This can pose a big problem when it comes time to sell because non-smoking buyers are sure to notice this residual aroma.

To make sure cigarette odors don’t cause your home sale to go up in smoke, there are three key tips you should follow when you list:

1. Have a full professional cleaning of your heating and cooling system. Cigarette smoke will get trapped in your home’s HVAC unit itself, so simply changing out the air filter won’t be enough if you hope to rid your house of odors. Having a professional clean the ductwork, and the unit itself, will be your ticket to fresh-smelling air.

2. Seal and repaint your walls and ceilings. Your home’s walls and ceilings can trap unpleasant-smelling nicotine particles, and painting alone won’t be enough to undo this effect. Instead, seal your walls first with a primer (like Kilz) and then add your fresh coat of paint after that.

3. Launder or steam-clean cloth items, carpet, and furniture in your home. Your drapes, chairs, couches, carpet, and more will all absorb the smell of cigarette smoke over time. Giving each of these items a thorough, professional cleaning will give a huge boost to your home’s overall freshness.

“Trapped odors from cigarette smoke can pose a big problem when it comes time to sell, because non-smoking buyers are sure to notice this residual aroma.”

As a bonus tip: Wipe down flat surfaces, knick-knacks, and light bulbs in your home. You may be surprised to learn that these items can contribute to how your home smells, but the difference that cleaning these things can make will speak for itself.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Don%2527t+Let+Your+Listing+Go+Up+In+Smoke.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Don%2527t+Let+Your+Listing+Go+Up+In+Smoke.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you smoke cigarettes in your home, the odors this habit leaves behind could cause your home sale to go up in smoke. Thankfully, there are three cleaning tips that can help alleviate this issue.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you smoke cigarettes in your home, the odors this habit leaves behind could cause your home sale to go up in smoke. Thankfully, there are three cleaning tips that can help alleviate this issue.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Were Thankful for All of You</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/were-thankful-for-all-of-you_16.html</link>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-15 12:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

At this time of year, we think about how much we have to be grateful for. Thanksgiving is a time to give, a time to love, and a time to reflect on things that mean the most in your life. This Thanksgiving, we are especially treasuring the weeks, hours, and minutes of time that we are able to spend with those that we care about. To all of our family, friends, neighbors, clients, and co-workers: We wish you a truly beautiful and bountiful Thanksgiving. We wrote a song called “You Are” that we think fits perfectly this time of year.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting

</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

At this time of year, we think about how much we have to be grateful for. Thanksgiving is a time to give, a time to love, and a time to reflect on things that mean the most in your life. This Thanksgiving, we are especially treasuring the weeks, hours, and minutes of time that we are able to spend with those that we care about. To all of our family, friends, neighbors, clients, and co-workers: We wish you a truly beautiful and bountiful Thanksgiving. We wrote a song called “You Are” that we think fits perfectly this time of year.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

At this time of year, we think about how much we have to be grateful for. Thanksgiving is a time to give, a time to love, and a time to reflect on things that mean the most in your life. This Thanksgiving, we are especially treasuring the weeks, hours, and minutes of time that we are able to spend with those that we care about. To all of our family, friends, neighbors, clients, and co-workers: We wish you a truly beautiful and bountiful Thanksgiving. We wrote a song called “You Are” that we think fits perfectly this time of year.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Keeping In Tune With The Market: Inside the Mind of a FSBO Seller</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/keeping-in-tune-with-market-inside-mind.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-12 10:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/April/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+Inside+The+Mind+Of+An+FSBO+Seller.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you, as an agent, convince a For Sale By Owner seller to work with you? It starts by jumping inside the mind of a FSBO seller.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


Welcome back to another episode of “Keeping In Tune With The Market.” Today, we’re going to get inside the mind of a homeowner who wants to list their home as For Sale By Owner (FSBO).

Would you like to get a listing this month? Sure, the market is tight and there’s not very much inventory, so what is the best way for you to get a new listing where you could help a homeowner sell their house?

Many agents shy away from FSBO listings because they think that when they go to those homeowners, they’ll get their heads bitten off. That’s actually not the case. By getting inside the head of a FSBO seller, we can understand that they might be a little less scary than you think.

Why would a person consider selling their home on their own instead of turning it over to a Realtor?

The first reason is to save on commission. A lot of them are just confident that they could sell on their own because, perhaps, they’ve sold cars or homes before. They might not know a good agent, or they might have had a bad experience with one. Many FSBO sellers feel as though they have a bottom line to reach and that they can’t afford to pay an agent. In that case, we have to show the owner how we can make them even more money than they could get on their own.

They might also think that if they can’t sell it on their own, then they can just turn it over to an agent. They might give it a few weeks to a couple months to try to sell on their own. In this case, find out what their motivation is. How soon do they need to move? Where are they going? Get an idea of how long they want to try it on their own.

“Many agents shy away from FSBO listings because they think that when they go to those homeowners, they’ll get their heads bitten off.”

Lastly, they feel like they want to get a particular bottom line. You will really be helpful to them if you can put them in touch with a mortgage broker or a financial expert so they can see how much money they really need from the sale of their house.

FSBO sellers aren’t as scary as you think. If you try to get on the other side of the able, get into their heads, and think about what their thought processes are, it might be a little easier for you to approach them.

If you’d like more information about working with FSBO sellers, I have a couple of trainers who have great plans. Just reach out to me, and I’ll be glad to send you that information. If you’d like to set up a strategy meeting to plan out your business for this year, we can set that up over coffee. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/April/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+Inside+The+Mind+Of+An+FSBO+Seller.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/April/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Getting+Inside+The+Mind+Of+An+FSBO+Seller.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How can you, as an agent, convince a For Sale By Owner seller to work with you? It starts by jumping inside the mind of a FSBO seller.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How can you, as an agent, convince a For Sale By Owner seller to work with you? It starts by jumping inside the mind of a FSBO seller.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get More Listings in 2018</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-get-more-listings-in-2018.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-25 12:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/January/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+More+Listings+in+2018.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to get more business, there is a key mantra you need to apply. That mantra is, “See. Call. Send.”


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


What are the best ways to get listings?

Today, I’ll be going over three tips you need to know to get more listings in 2018.

The first question you need to ask yourself is, “Who are the best people to get listings from?” A lot of people will say you should look into things like cold calling and door knocking. These things are fine, but the fact is that about 75% of your listings will come from people who already know you.

This means that the majority of listings you get will come from friends, family, co-workers, and other people in your sphere of influence. The people who know you are the ones who will do business with you.

“The people who know you are the ones who will do business with you.”

Now, let’s move on to the three ways to get listings from these people. It all comes down to the mantra: “See. Call. Send.” Let me expand a little on this.

1. See. Checking in with the people you know will help you stay connected. It doesn’t always have to be about real estate. The important thing is that you are keeping in touch and maintaining these relationships.

2. Call. It’s important to give the people you know a call every once in a while. The market has gone up dramatically, so consider asking people if they’re curious about their home’s value.

3. Send. Distribute newsletters and notifications to people in your sphere of influence via the mail. The mail you send can be informative, educational, and entertaining. While you’re at it, you could even start sending out videos.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/January/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+More+Listings+in+2018.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2018/January/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+More+Listings+in+2018.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to get more business, there is a key mantra you need to apply. That mantra is, “See. Call. Send.”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to get more business, there is a key mantra you need to apply. That mantra is, “See. Call. Send.”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Check Out This New Music Video Featuring the Donovan 3</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/check-out-this-new-music-video.html</link>
        
          <category>The Donovan Team</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-19 12:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2017/December/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Check+Out+This+New+Music+Video+Featuring+the+Donovan+3.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, the Donovan 3 are singing their rendition of “Do You Believe in Christmas?”


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


We’re almost to the end of the year, and the holiday season is in full swing with happy people everywhere. Here at Donovan Home Sales, there’s something magic in the air.  If you hear a song and start to hum along, it may just be the Donovan 3 singing their rendition of “Do You Believe in Christmas?” If you want a reason to get into the holiday spirit and enjoy a catchy, festive tune, go ahead and watch our new music video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2017/December/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Check+Out+This+New+Music+Video+Featuring+the+Donovan+3.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2017/December/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Check+Out+This+New+Music+Video+Featuring+the+Donovan+3.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, the Donovan 3 are singing their rendition of “Do You Believe in Christmas?”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, the Donovan 3 are singing their rendition of “Do You Believe in Christmas?”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Break Into Real Estate Without Breaking the Bank</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/break-into-real-estate-without-breaking.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-17 11:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2017/November/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Break+Into+Real+Estate+Without+Breaking+the+Bank.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome back to another episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.” Today’s question is: How can a new real estate agent break into the business without breaking the bank?


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


Welcome back to another episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.”

Today’s question is: How can a new real estate agent break into the business without breaking the bank?

So, you’ve got your brand-new real estate license and you’re excited to begin. Then, things start popping up. You’re told you must subscribe to this coach or pay for that class. The issue is that all of these kinds of things cost money. But I’m here to tell you that all is not lost.

You can get great training for free. It is possible. The first thing I recommend is that you look into a program called RealtyJuggler. When you sign up at www.RealtyJuggler.com you can get a 90-day subscription for free, and it really does the job.

“It is possible to get great training for free.”

RealtyJuggler will help you learn how to consistently prospect, stay organized, develop a database, and have a great mindset. There are a lot of great features on the site. In the contact section, you can add all of your friends, relatives, neighbors, coworkers, and anyone else right into your database.

Once you’ve plugged in the email addresses of all of these contacts, you can begin to prospect. I’ve got a couple of resources I’d like to share that can help you do this. First, www.MikeFerryTV.com is a great, free resource for scripts, dialogue, and training.

Another place to get information is on Kevin Ward’s video blog. And, of course, we can’t forget Mr. Tom Ferry. Visit his website here for some great tips.

We also have our own career-building video blog, which you can find here. If you would like some training on a particular topic, you can feel free to ask me a question at any time.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2017/November/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Break+Into+Real+Estate+Without+Breaking+the+Bank.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Videos/2017/November/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Break+Into+Real+Estate+Without+Breaking+the+Bank.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Welcome back to another episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.” Today’s question is: How can a new real estate agent break into the business without breaking the bank?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Welcome back to another episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.” Today’s question is: How can a new real estate agent break into the business without breaking the bank?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Identify and Handle a Stroke</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-identify-and-handle-stroke.html</link>
        
          <category>Stroke</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-07 12:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Identify+and+Handle+a+Stroke.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Knowing what to do when you spot a stroke is critical—the right knowledge could save a life.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


I wanted to do something a little different for today’s episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.” Today, I want to talk about a very serious subject: strokes.

Imagine you’re with family over the holiday season when suddenly you notice a loved one’s face beginning to droop on one side—one side of their body appears weak and they’re now slurring their speech.

What do you do? First, it’s time to call 911. These warning signs should never be ignored.

Two weeks ago when my own mother began exhibiting these symptoms, my sisters were thankfully able to recognize the signs and get her immediate medical treatment.

It is critical that people who have had or are having a stroke receive medical attention within the first three hours.

Unfortunately, I have first-hand experience where another family member was not so fortunate. My sister-in-law had a stroke around the same time as my mother. She was out of the town at the time and went to a walk-in clinic where they told her it was probably just her back.

“Warning signs should never be ignored.”

They sent her home and she suffered a massive stroke. As a result of not receiving prompt and immediate attention, her injuries will be long-term, if not permanent.

You may be wondering why I’ve chosen to talk about this when my usual subjects relate to real estate. The truth is that real estate is about family and home. That’s why today I chose to share this information with you—to protect your family.

The easiest way to spot and handle a stroke is to remember “F.A.S.T.,” which stands for face drooping, arm weakness, speech difficulty, and time to call 911.

Whether it is you or a family member experiencing these symptoms, do not wait. Getting immediate emergency medical treatment is absolutely key.

I hope you and your family stay happy, healthy, and able to enjoy your home.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Identify+and+Handle+a+Stroke.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Identify+and+Handle+a+Stroke.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Knowing what to do when you spot a stroke is critical—the right knowledge could save a life.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Knowing what to do when you spot a stroke is critical—the right knowledge could save a life.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are Some Subtle Ways to Get Sellers to Do What You Want?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-are-some-subtle-ways-to-get.html</link>
        
          <category>Tampa Bay Realtor Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-28 13:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+Sellers+to+Do+What+You+Want.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you have a seller whose house needs work, there are five tactful ways to get them to do what you want.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


Today I want to talk about five tricks you can use to get a seller to do what you want. Well, they’re not really “tricks” — they’re more like tips.

Let’s say you have a seller and you know there are things on their house that need to be changed or fixed. Either you saw them when you first walked in the door, they were brought to your attention as time went by and you looked closer at the property, or a fellow Realtor brought it up to you during an inspection. In any case, should you lay it all on the seller with your bottom line very sternly and risk them getting annoyed with you?

“Help your seller feel that you’re understanding.”

That’s probably not the best way of doing things. There are five ways to be more tactful:

1. Be compassionate. You might not know what the situation is with that particular seller. They may be getting divorced, going through a job transfer, dealing with a death in the family, etc. If you do know, you need to be compassionate, give them a little space, and help them feel that you’re understanding.

2. Create a to-do list. I had a seller recently whose house wasn’t too bad, but we got a lot of feedback about its patio and yard being unkempt. Instead of just telling them they had to do some repainting and lay some sod down, we sat down with them and made a to-do list. They were on board with it, and they did most of the things on that list.

3. Involve the seller. Ask them what they think they can do to help with the process.

4. Suggest some low-cost alternatives. Maybe it’s just a paint job and some power washing. Maybe you know a handyman who can help them. Maybe they need a low-cost storage unit to help them declutter.

5. Offer options. If there is a seller who is elderly and can’t make the necessary repairs, then you make an alternative solution such as a credit at the closing. This way they won’t have to do a lot of work if they feel as though they don’t have the energy or the monetary wherewithal.

If you have any questions about this topic, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to seeing you at the next episode of “Keeping in Tune With the Market.” Until then, make it a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+Sellers+to+Do+What+You+Want.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+Sellers+to+Do+What+You+Want.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you have a seller whose house needs work, there are five tactful ways to get them to do what you want.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you have a seller whose house needs work, there are five tactful ways to get them to do what you want.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Keeping in Tune With the Market: How to Get Your Offer Accepted Without Breaking the Bank</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/keeping-in-tune-with-market-how-to-get.html</link>
        
          <category>Tampa Bay Realtor Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-17 14:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Strategies+to+Get+Your+Home+Offer+Accepted.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a homebuyer competing against other offers on the same home, here are three strategies you can use to make your offer stand out.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


Today I’m answering a question from Amanda Fabian, who asks, “How do I get my offer accepted when there are four other competing offers on a home?”

First of all, congratulations to Amanda, who will receive a $10 Panera gift card for her question being chosen.

To get your offer accepted when there are other competing offers on the same home, I have three strategies you can use:

1. Make your offer as competitive as you can without going over your budget. If you’re going with a higher financing amount, you must be competitive against someone who might be putting more cash into the deal. Also, make sure you have your pre-approval letter and that you submit it at the same time you put your offer in. Your offer must be as strong as possible.

2. Find out from the other agent or owner what their hot buttons are. In other words, does the owner want a quick closing or do they need extra time? When you structure your offer, make sure to add that in. Does the owner have a special appliance they want to take with them? Stress that the appliance can go with the owner and you don’t insist on having it stay.

3. Write a personal note from the heart. This one is my secret weapon. When you do this, find out a little bit about the owner and share with them some information about your family and how you will love the home as much as they did. If you have a cute little kid or puppy, include pictures of them in the note.

“Your offer must be as strong as possible.”

If you have a real estate question that’s on your mind, don’t hesitate to email it to me. If I answer it in a future video, you’ll receive a $10 gift card. Until next time, make it a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Strategies+to+Get+Your+Home+Offer+Accepted.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Strategies+to+Get+Your+Home+Offer+Accepted.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re a homebuyer competing against other offers on the same home, here are three strategies you can use to make your offer stand out.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re a homebuyer competing against other offers on the same home, here are three strategies you can use to make your offer stand out.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Season's Greetings from the Donovan Team</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-donovan-team.html</link>
        
          <category>The Donovan Team</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-09 14:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It may surprise some of you to know that we at the Donovan Team are as passionate about music as we are about real estate! Please check out this year’s Singing Christmas Card!


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


With the holidays in full swing, we wanted to share something special with you today.

As many of you may know from prior posts - when we aren’t busy helping our clients buy and sell real estate or helping our team members design their dream real estate career,  we love writing and performing music!

We are proud to present our 5th Annual Singing Christmas card for your musical entertainment! This year’s presentation is entitled: “Memories Are Evergreen”. With guest vocalist Paul Donovan on lead, Joe Donovan, musical producer on harmonica, and Karen Donovan, singer/song writer, on backup vocals. Warning - this video could bring a tear to your eye as you recall happy memories from your past!

Click here to hear the track and see the music video, which is comprised of our home movies from years ago. You may even recognize a few members of the Donovan Brothers Realty team in it!

“Wishing you and your loved ones a Christmas &amp; Holiday Season that is truly Evergreen!”

From all of us at the Donovan Team, we’d like to wish  all of our Clients, Friends, Colleagues &amp; Loved ones a Blessed Holiday and Happy and Healthy New Year and may all your wishes come true!

In the meantime, if we can help you or a Real Estate Colleague you care about with Real Estate endevors 2017 - don’t hesitate to give us a call!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

It may surprise some of you to know that we at the Donovan Team are as passionate about music as we are about real estate! Please check out this year’s Singing Christmas Card!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It may surprise some of you to know that we at the Donovan Team are as passionate about music as we are about real estate! Please check out this year’s Singing Christmas Card!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Texting for Dollars Can Grow Your Business</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-texting-for-dollars-can-grow-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-21 12:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Finish+2016+strong+by+texting+for+dollars+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to finish the year strong, I recommend that you start texting for dollars. Texting is a great way to get an immediate response from potential clients.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


If you’re like me, as you approach the end of the year, you might think that you are running out of steam or you’re running out of people in your pipeline. However, you still want to finish the year strong. One way you can still end 2016 on a high note is to incorporate texting for dollars.

I don’t know about you, but if I get an email, I put it in my line of emails that I have to reply to and I might get to it or I might not. If I get a voicemail, the same thing happens. Sometimes my voicemails wait awhile for a response. But what about a text?

A text is immediate. People always have their phones on and people will see it right away. How do you text for dollars? Here is an example of a text you could send out:

“Hi Janet. The market’s really moving and prices are going up, up, up. Are you curious about your home’s value or know someone who needs my help???” Then, hit send! Hopefully, Janet will give me a call.

The fact of the matter is people are curious about their home’s value. Texting for dollars is a great way to get a CMA to someone who might be thinking about making a move this year or next year.

“A text is immediate.”

Who should you text? Anyone in your database who bought a house 10 years ago. Back then, the market was up kind of high, but it went down. Now the market is almost back to where it was, and it might be time for those homeowners to consider selling again because they should have enough equity to do so.

You should also text people who are thinking about retiring. A lot of people in the older age bracket pride themselves on being able to text, so this is a great opportunity to reach out to them.

In short, texting for dollars is a great way to finish the year strong. If you have any questions, give me a call or send me an email. Don’t forget to submit your questions for our next video; send me one and you will enter the contest for a $25 gift certificate. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Finish+2016+strong+by+texting+for+dollars+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Finish+2016+strong+by+texting+for+dollars+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to finish the year strong, I recommend that you start texting for dollars. Texting is a great way to get an immediate response from potential clients.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to finish the year strong, I recommend that you start texting for dollars. Texting is a great way to get an immediate response from potential clients.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Major Mortgage Mistakes Tampa Buyers Should Avoid</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/tampa-bay-real-estate-careers-avoiding.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-16 11:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Karen+Donovan+%25288-10-2016%2529+Mortgage+Mistakes+Careers+TAMPA.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I received an email from a colleague the other day and it was so upsetting that I thought, “Wow, we have to talk about how to avoid the heartbreak of major mortgage mistakes.”


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


This buyer had been in the army and felt that he “hadn’t had a place to call home since.” He was about to close on the property when the lender sent an email requesting more paperwork, pushing the closing back another month.

The buyer had sent in his application on time and paid for inspections and appraisals. Unfortunately, the lender never sent the application to underwriting. When the buyer asked why everything took so long, the lender cited staffing issues. Because of this, the buyer didn’t have a home to move into when his lease was up. As the buyer said, this finance company failed.

How do we as buyers, sellers, or Realtors avoid major mortgage headaches like this?

First of all, make sure you work with a local, reputable lender. Get recommendations from friends and colleagues. Hire someone who has done many transactions. Please, don’t search online for lenders and hire one from a different state. They won’t know any appraisers in our area, and that can only lead to headaches.

“Work with a reputable local lender.”

Make sure that the money the buyer needs to close is in the bank. That means they have enough to cover the downpayment and closing costs. Also, make sure they know not to run up additional debts by purchasing a car or furniture between contract and closing; doing so will also cause trouble with your mortgage.

Finally, make sure that you call your lender with any questions. Make sure the buyer is pre-approved, not just pre-qualified. As a Realtor, it is your responsibility to make sure all lines of communication are open.

If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Karen+Donovan+%25288-10-2016%2529+Mortgage+Mistakes+Careers+TAMPA.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+Karen+Donovan+%25288-10-2016%2529+Mortgage+Mistakes+Careers+TAMPA.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I received an email from a colleague the other day and it was so upsetting that I thought, “Wow, we have to talk about how to avoid the heartbreak of major mortgage mistakes.”

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I received an email from a colleague the other day and it was so upsetting that I thought, “Wow, we have to talk about how to avoid the heartbreak of major mortgage mistakes.”

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lets Get You Out of Your Summer Slump</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/tampa-bay-real-estate-careers-get-out.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Career Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-20 12:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Careers-+Get+out+of+that+summer+lull.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome back to another edition of our blog highlighting real estate tips, trends, and strategies. The summer is when many agents get into a slump in their business. If they had a good spring, they feel fine with the slump as it happens, only to regret it toward the end of the year.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


Many agents I’ve spoken to over the years tend to blame their lack of summer production on a lack of good leads. When we first got into the business, we decided to make a list of everyone we knew. We made a commitment to add to that list daily and send those folks on our list relevant and interesting information on a periodic basis. A lot of agents I talk to think this is a great idea, but make excuses for themselves like not having enough time to get a list together or not knowing enough people.

“I really want to help you do this.”

If you’re slowing down a bit during the summer, this is a great exercise. Make a list of all the people you know, and make a commitment to add to that list. I really want to help you do this, so I will be doing two things for you as well, personally. First, I’ll send you a dynamite memory jogger to help you remember those people you always seem to forget. Secondly, I will be your accountability partner for one week. Tell me how many names you want to add to your database in a week’s time, and I will be in contact with you to make sure you’re successful.

If you have any questions for me at all, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. Your real estate success is my concern. As always, make it a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Careers-+Get+out+of+that+summer+lull.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Careers-+Get+out+of+that+summer+lull.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Professional Photos Are Crucial for Your Tampa Bay Sale</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/tampa-bay-real-estate-agent-case-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-01 11:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+case+for+professional+photography.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’ve probably all seen the mistake of poorly photographed properties listed for sale in Long Island. Did you know that 92% of buyers start their search on the Internet for homes? I have 3 main reasons to use professional photography when selling your Long Island home.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


1. You only get one chance to make a good first impression.

2. They take high-quality HD photos with good lighting and a wide-angle lens to show your entire space. We don’t want to deceive people and make the home look bigger than it really is, but you do want things to look attractive, well-lit, and not grainy in your photos.

“You only get one chance to make a good first impression.”

3. Once you have the professional quality photographs, you can utilize them in multiple ways. Your agent can post the photos to Facebook and on numerous websites, as well as virtual tours of your listing.

If you’re going to use photos of your home online, it’s really a no-brainer whether or not you should use a professional photographer. If you have any further questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me! I’d love to help in any way that I can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+case+for+professional+photography.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+case+for+professional+photography.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tampa Bay Real Estate Tips: How to E-Sign a Document Via Email</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/tampa-bay-real-estate-agent-scoop-about.html</link>
        
          <category>Tampa Bay Realtor Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-05-06 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+scoop+about+DocuSign+for+agents.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Whether you’re 18 or 80 years old, there will be some point where you will sign a document via email. This tool saves a lot of time, especially in the real estate industry.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


It’s incredibly simple. Let’s review a brief demo. First, fill in your personal information. Next, review and act on these documents. You’re already at the point where you need to sign once you read everything over. At the bottom of the page, you sign to agree to the document’s conditions. You can see I’ve already chosen a signature that reflects my own handwriting. Lastly, click finish.

“This tool saves a lot of time, especially in the real estate industry.”

It’s that easy! Now you know how to sign a document electronically, in case you’re ever asked to. If you have any questions about this topic or more, please contact me. I’m available by both phone and email! I look forward to hearing your questions, suggestions for future topics, feedback, and more.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+scoop+about+DocuSign+for+agents.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+scoop+about+DocuSign+for+agents.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Whether you’re 18 or 80 years old, there will be some point where you will sign a document via email. This tool saves a lot of time, especially in the real estate industry.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Whether you’re 18 or 80 years old, there will be some point where you will sign a document via email. This tool saves a lot of time, especially in the real estate industry.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of a Stand-Up Desk</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/tampa-bay-real-estate-agent-is-stand-up.html</link>
        
          <category>Stand-up Desks</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-08 12:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent+Is+a+stand-up+desk+right+for+you.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve heard a lot about stand-up desks, and how it might be great to already be standing-up when others approach your workspace. Standing-up, compared to sitting all day, prevents back problems and other pains. Your arms are at a nice resting place.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


However, I didn’t want to go out and spend a few hundred dollars on a brand-new stand-up desk. I ended up learning about this awesome company called Oristand. I ordered this desk, similar to cardboard, that looks great. It’s also affordable and portable. I can move it around, take it down, and bring it home with me.

You add your laptop or computer monitor to the top shelf, and add a wireless keyboard to the bottom one. It goes on top of your desk or other surface, transforming your previous workspace into something trendy and healthy. When you start working, you can turn your computer on and are ready to go. You’re already eye-level with your computer. Your arms and shoulders feel relaxed, since you aren’t scrunched into a sitting position.

When you’re talking to clients, you have a lot more energy and flexibility when you’re standing. The other day, I noticed one of our team members leaned over on their laptop. After a while, I could tell she ran out of energy because her neck looked like it hurt. If you have some shoulder pain, or would like a change in lifestyle to benefit your health, consider investing in an Oristand stand-up desk. It’s a great way to learn if this type of desk is for you!

If you have any questions about today’s video, or anything else, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be delighted to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent+Is+a+stand-up+desk+right+for+you.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent+Is+a+stand-up+desk+right+for+you.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I’ve heard a lot about stand-up desks, and how it might be great to already be standing-up when others approach your workspace. Standing-up, compared to sitting all day, prevents back problems and other pains. Your arms are at a nice resting place.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I’ve heard a lot about stand-up desks, and how it might be great to already be standing-up when others approach your workspace. Standing-up, compared to sitting all day, prevents back problems and other pains. Your arms are at a nice resting place.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title> Real Estate Tips, Trends, and Strategies: Group Texts</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/tampa-bay-real-estate-agent-how-group.html</link>
        
          <category>Group text Messaging</category>
        
          <category>Tampa Bay Realtor Tips</category>
        
        <author>Karen & Joe Donovan</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-15 11:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent+How+group+text+messaging+works.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we are talking about the etiquette of group texting. Here in Tampa Bay, everyone with a cell phone is in some kind of group text or another.


Ask us a question
Set up a Skype or coffee meeting


There are a lot of nuances to group messaging that you may not even be aware of. You’ve probably gotten a text from a friend before, who also sent the message to other people. Then you quickly reply with a personal message but don’t realize it’s being sent to everyone else, even people you may not know.

“We just wanted to share this quick tip with you.”

We recently had one of our agents tell us they didn’t even know this was possible. They thought when you replied to a group text, you were only replying to the sender. But no, that’s not how group text messaging works. Everyone gets every message unless you do one of two things.

The first thing you can do is look down to the bottom of the message, and uncheck the check mark to simply reply to the person who sent the text. Or better yet, start a new message to the particular person you want to. This way, your messages won’t be broadcast to the entire world.

We just wanted to share this quick tip with you this week because we thought it would be helpful. If you have any questions for us, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent+How+group+text+messaging+works.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Donovans+(Tampa+Bay)/Tampa+Bay+Real+Estate+Agent+How+group+text+messaging+works.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today we are talking about the etiquette of group texting. Here in Tampa Bay, everyone with a cell phone is in some kind of group text or another.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Karen & Joe Donovan</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today we are talking about the etiquette of group texting. Here in Tampa Bay, everyone with a cell phone is in some kind of group text or another.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tampa Bay, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Karen & Joe Donovan</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Karen & Joe Donovan</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Donovan Home Sales, Inc. - your professional Tampa Bay Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
